iclasspro.com 2019-12-20

# iClassPro Privacy Policy - iClassPro Class Management Software - Gymnastics, Cheer, Swim, and Dance

Updated and Effective Date:  July 5, 2018

**Our Commitment to Privacy**  
iClassPro’s Privacy Policy was developed as an extension of our commitment to combine the highest-quality products and services with the highest level of integrity in dealing with our clients and partners. The Policy is designed to assist you in understanding how we collect, use and safeguard the personal information you provide to us and to assist you in making informed decisions when using our site and our products and services. This statement will be continuously assessed by us against new technologies, business practices, and our customers' needs.

**Definitions**

  * “You” and “your” mean the individual or entity visiting or using our Website(s).
  * “We,” “us” and “our” means iClassPro.
  * “Website” refers to iClassPro’s website, [www.iclasspro.com](http://www.iclasspro.com/), and other associated websites, blogs, domains and mobile sites maintained by iClassPro.
  * “Personal information” means personally identifiable information, which is non-public information we receive from your use of the Website that can be use, alone or in combination with other information in our possession, to identify a particular individual.  It may include information such as name, address, telephone number and other personal information you provide to us.

**Information Do We Collect**  
When you visit our website(s), which include [www.iclasspro.com](http://www.iclasspro.com/) and any associated websites that we operate on the [www.iclasspro.com](http://www.iclasspro.com/) domain and/or use the iClassPro Application, which includes the iClassPro Parent Portal, (collectively referred to as the “Websites”) you may provide us with three types of information: 1.) Personal information you knowingly choose to disclose that is collected on an individual basis, 2.) Website use information collected on an aggregate basis as you and others browse our Website and 3.) Email link tracking.

  1. _Personal Information You Choose to Provide_

**Credit Card Information**  
If you choose to purchase products or services from us, our partners, or (in the case of using the iClassPro Parent Portal) the facility that is associated with the iClassPro Parent Portal main account, you may need to give personal information and authorization to obtain information from various credit services. For example, you may need to provide the following information:

• Name  
• Mailing address  
• Email address  
• Credit card number  
• Home and business phone numbers  
• Other personal information (i.e. mother’s maiden name)

**Email Information**  
In addition to providing the foregoing information to our partners and the facility that is associated with the iClassPro Parent Portal main account, if you choose to correspond further with us through email and/or support and suggestion tickets, we may retain the content of your email messages and/or tickets together with your email address and our responses. We provide the same protections for these electronic communications that we employ in the maintenance of information received by mail and telephone.

**Additional Information Collected through the iClassPro Parent Portal**

We also collect and share, as necessary, with our partners and the facility that is associated with the iClassPro Parent Portal main account, personal information about your child through the iClassPro Parent Portal that you choose to provide us.  This information about your child may include:

  * Name
  * Date of birth
  * Gender
  * Association Identification (e.g., USA Gymnastics Association)
  * Medical information
  * Photograph for identification
  * School grade

2\. _Website Use Information_

Similar to other commercial websites and/or web applications, our Website and/or the iClassPro Application utilizes a standard technology called “cookies” (see explanation below, “What Are Cookies?”) and web server logs to collect information about how our Website and/or the iClassPro Application is used. Information gathered through cookies and web server logs may include your web browser information, language, current IP address, the date and time of visits, the pages viewed, time spent at our Website, other usage data, and the web sites visited just before and just after our Website. This information is collected on an aggregate basis. None of this information is associated with you as an individual.

**How We Use the Information That You Provide to Us**  
Broadly speaking, we use personal information for purposes of administering our business activities, providing customer service, developing products and services, and making available other products and services to our customers and prospective customers. Occasionally, we may also use the information we collect to notify you about important changes to our Website and/or iClassPro’s products or services, and new services and special offers we think you will find valuable. The lists used to send you product and service offers are developed and managed under our traditional corporate standards designed to safeguard the security and privacy of our customers’ personal information. As a customer, you will be given the opportunity in each communication to notify us of your desire not to receive these offers.

**COOKIES**  
Cookies are a feature of web browser software that allows web servers to recognize the computer used to access a website. Cookies are small pieces of data that are stored by a user’s web browser on the user’s hard drive. Cookies can remember what information a user accesses on one webpage to simplify subsequent interactions with that web site by the same user or to use the information to streamline the user’s transactions on related webpages. This makes it easier for a user to move from webpage to webpage and to complete commercial transactions over the Internet. Cookies should make your online experience easier and more personalized.

**Information We Collect from Cookies**  
We use website browser software tools such as cookies and web server logs to gather information about our Website users’ browsing activities.  Cookies help us collect important business and technical statistics. The information in the cookies lets us trace the paths followed by users to our Website as they move from one page to another. Web server logs allow us to count how many people visit our Website and evaluate our Website’s visitor capacity. We do not use these technologies to capture your individual email address or any personally identifying information about you, although they do permit us to send focused online banner advertisements or other such responses to you.

When you visit our site, or the sites of our partners, we might send you cookies to store your preferences and improve the quality of our service to you. Any cookies may be deleted following each session.  Third-party services and tools may also send you cookies to collect certain information from users, which includes:

_Google AdWords Conversion, Google Dynamic Remarketing, Google AdWords User Lists, Google Tag Manager, GA Audiences and Google Analytics, Double Click, and Double Click Ad Manager (collectively referred to as “Google”):_  Google collects anonymous data (ad views, analytics, browser information, cookie data, date/time, demographic data, hardware/software type, internet service provider, interaction data, page views, and serving domains), pseudonymous data (IP Address (EU PII), Device ID (EU PII), PII (name, address, phone number, email address, login, EU- IP address, EU-unique device ID ), sensitive (financial information). Aggregate data, anonymous data, PII data and sensitive data is shared by Google with third-party parties.  We use the information we get from Google only to improve this website and for marketing purposes.  Google collects only the IP address assigned to you on the date you visit this website, rather than your name or other identifying information.  You can review Google’s privacy policy at <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>.  Although Google plants a permanent cookie on your web browser to identify you as a unique user the next time you visit this website, the cookie cannot be used by anyone but Google.  Google’s ability to use and share information collected by Google about your visits to this website is restricted by the Google Terms of Use and the Google Privacy Policy.  You can prevent Google from recognizing you on return visits to the website by disabling cookies on your browser (see below).

Facebook Custom Audience: Facebook Custom Audience is operated by Facebook Business (formerly Facebook Custom Audience), collects: anonymous data (ad views, analytics, browser information, cookie data, date/time, demographic data, hardware/software type, internet service provider, interaction data, page views, and serving domains), pseudonymous data (IP Address (EU PII), search history, location based data, Clickstream Data, PII (name , address, phone number, email address, login, EU- IP address, EU-unique device ID ), sensitive (financial information).  Facebook Custom Audience’s privacy policy can be found at:  [https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy. ](https://www.facebook.com/full_data_use_policy.%C2%A0);

Facebook for Developers (formerly Facebook Connect):Facebook for Developers collects:anonymous data (ad views, analytics, browser information, cookie data, date/time, demographic data, hardware/software type, internet service provider, interaction data, page views, and serving domains), pseudonymous data (IP Address (EU PII), search history, location based data, Clickstream Data, PII (name , address, phone number, email address, login, EU- IP address, EU-unique device ID ), sensitive (financial information).Facebook for Developers’ privacy policy can be found at:<https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/>

Zendesk and Zopin:Zendesk owns and operates Zopin.Zendesk and Zopin collect:anonymous data (browser information, cookie data, date/time, hardware/software type, internet service provider, and page views), pseudonymous data (IP Address (EU PII), and Clickstream Data.Data collected by Zendesk is shared with third parties.Zendesk’s and Zopin’s privacy policy can be found at:<https://www.zendesk.com/company/privacy/>

Each of the above-listed services and tools listed is governed by the privacy policy established by the respective third party provider.  We encourage you to refer to such policies, which are linked to above in the description of each service.

 _Restricting Cookies_

Some browsers may allow you to manage the storage of cookies on your device.  If supported by your browser, you may set your browser to refuse all cookies (or, sometimes all third party cookies) or to alert you when a cookie is set.  However, if you select these settings, you may be unable to access certain parts of this website.  Unless you have adjusted your browser setting to refuse cookies, our system will issue cookies.  For more information about how to manage your cookies preferences, use the “help” menu of your web browser or explore the customer support sections of your web browser.  To opt-out of all cookies or certain advertising cookies, visit the company website for your browser.  

Most browsers allow you to set preferences regarding the download of cookies, or block the download. Note that if you choose to block these cookies, some or all of the services we provide may not function. Here are links to some browsers’ websites:

  * Google Chrome: [http://www.google.com](http://www.google.com/)
  * Internet Explorer: support.microsoft.com
  * Mozilla Firefox: support.mozilla.org
  * Safari: support.apple.com
  * Opera: [http://www.opera.com](http://www.opera.com/)

3\. Email link tracking

When iClassPro, Inc. sends email regarding our products and services, we may use various tracking methods that collect information about email delivery status, opens/views and clicks within the contents of the emails.  When users of the iClassPro application send an email from within the application, the same tracking methods may be employed.

**How We Use the Data We Collect**

We collect only as much personal information as we need for specific, declared purposes, and will not use it for other purposes without obtaining your consent.

The purposes for which we use your information, in addition to any reasons stated above, include:

  * Providing our products or services.
  * Research, analysis and auditing, in order to improve our products and services, or to protect or maintain the same.
  * Maintaining and ensuring the viability and integrity of our network.
  * Marketing and promotional efforts.
  * Sending newsletters.
  * Protecting the rights or property of iClassPro, or our users or partners.
  * Creating, researching and developing new products and services.
  * General communications with you.

**LENGTH OF TIME WE RETAIN YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

iClassPro retains personal information for as long as necessary to fulfill the business purpose for which you provided it to us and any other legitimate business purpose, including without limitation, for the purposes of satisfying any legal, accounting, or reporting requirements.  We may also retain offline archival copies of data for the applicable statutory periods.  If you would like more details about our data retention policies, please contact us.

We periodically review our collection, storage and processing procedures and policies to ensure that it is in compliance with applicable law.

**Information We Share With Third Parties**

Except as described in this policy, we will not share your personal information with third parties without your consent. For personal information received by iClassPro under the Privacy Shield and disclosed to a third party, iClassPro remains responsible and liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if a third party engages with the personal data in a manner inconsistent with the principles of the Privacy Shield, unless iClassPro proves that it is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage.

We will only share your personal information with the following types of third parties for the following purposes:

  * Fulfilling services.  We share personal information with the relevant third parties related to providing the products or services you have purchased or subscribed to, which include without limitation, partners and subcontractors that are utilized for the purpose of operating the Website or fulfilling the products or services requested by you, and the facility that is associated with the iClassPro Parent Portal main account.
  * If we have your consent to share personal information for a purpose different than what your personal information was provided.
  * For processing of said information. The companies, partners or affiliates who process this information agree to do so in accordance with our instructions, and according to this privacy policy.
  * If iClassPro is involved in any merger, acquisition or any other form of sale. We will endeavor to protect the privacy of personal information, and notify you before such sale or acquisition, and the transfer to a new privacy policy, if applicable.
  * For carrying out any of the functions or purposes set forth in the section titled, “How We use the data we collect”

Additionally, be aware that we may be required to disclose an individual's personal information in response to a valid legal requirement, such as in response to a lawful request by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements, search warrant, subpoena, court order; or in special cases, such as in response to a physical threat to you or others, to protect property, or assert legal rights or defend ourselves in litigation.  If iClassPro is legally compelled to disclose your personal information to a third party, we will attempt to notify you unless doing so would violate the law or a court order.

**TRANSFER OF DATA UPON SALE OR CHANGE OF OWNERSHIP OF ICLASSPRO**

In the event that the Website (or a substantial portion of our assets) is acquired, your information would be considered part of those assets and may be part of those assets that are transferred.

**How We Secure Information Transmissions**  
When you send confidential personal credit card information to us on our Website, a secure server software which we have licensed encrypts all information you input before it is sent to us. The information is scrambled en route and decoded once it reaches our Website.

Other emails that you may send to us may not be secure unless we advise you that security measures will be in place prior to your transmitting the information. For that reason, we ask that you do not send confidential information such as Social Security or account numbers to us through an unsecured email.

**How Do We Protect Your Information**

_Information Security_.  
We utilize encryption/security software to safeguard the confidentiality of personal information we collect to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure and accidental loss, alteration or destruction of personal information.

_Evaluation of Information Protection Practices_.  
Periodically, our operations and business practices are reviewed for compliance with corporate policies and procedures governing the security, confidentiality, and quality of our information.

_Employee Access, Training, and Expectations_.  
Our corporate values, ethical standards, policies, and practices are committed to the protection of customer information. In general, our business practices limit employee access to confidential information and limit the use and disclosure of such information to authorized persons, processes, and transactions.

**HOW YOU CAN Access and Control YOUR Personal Data**

_Individual Rights to Access Personal Data_

Individuals have the right to know what personal data of theirs is stored by iClassPro and to ensure that such personal data is accurate and relevant for the purposes for which iClassPro collected it. iClassPro will make its best effort to allow individuals access to view their own data as well as to correct, to alter or to delete such data.

However, where such access is unreasonable, requires a disproportionate effort, jeopardizes the privacy of other iClassPro users, or contravenes the law, our policies, or reasonable business practice, requests to access data may be declined. User identification is required to access data for these reasons, and the process and procedures for various types of access may differ. Please contact us for further information.

_Choices Relating to Use of Personal Information_

We'll give you choices about the ways we use and share your personal information, and we'll respect the choices you make. Although signing up for some or all of our services may require you to submit personal information, we will ask for your consent if we intend to use that information for any purpose other than which it was provided to us.  You may object, restrict or withdraw consent for us to use your personal information at any time.

In the case of us wishing to use your private information for any purpose different than the purpose it was provided and set forth in this Privacy Policy, we will request your consent to use your personal information and will only use it if you affirmatively give us consent to do so through an opt in process.

You may choose to decline to submit any personal information for any of our products or services. Please note that this may result in our being unable to provide said service, including, without limitation, subscription services, even if time remains for your subscription. 

**California Privacy Rights**

Under Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, residents of California can obtain certain information from companies with whom they have an established business relationship.  That information is about the personal information those companies have shared with third parties for direct marketing purposes during the preceding calendar year.  The law requires companies to inform consumers about the categories of personally information shared with third parties, the names and addresses of those third parties, and examples of the services or products marketed by those third parties.  To request a copy of the information disclosure provided by iClassPro under Section 1798.83 of the California Civil Code, please contact us.

**Children’s Privacy Protection  **

iClassPro takes special care to protect the privacy needs of children under the age of 13 and iClassPro encourages parents to be an active participant in their child’s online activities.  iClassPro abides by the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA) and other relevant laws.  The website does not target and is not intended for children under the age of 13, and iClassPro will not knowingly collect personal information from them.  If iClassPro discovers personal data from a child gathered through the website, without parental consent, iClassPro will eliminate that data.  This website is not intended for persons under the age of 13.  If you are under 13 you must ask a parent or legal guardian for permission prior to submitting any information to this website.

**Do Not Track Notice   **

Your browser may provide you with the option to send a “Do Not Track” signal to websites you visit.  This signal is used to request that websites not send the requesting device cookies, but websites have no obligation to respond to such signal or to modify their operation.  At the current time, this website is not programmed to recognize Do Not Track signals, so this website will not treat you differently if we receive such signals from your browser and we may not comply with Do Not Track settings on your browser.

**  Third-Party Sites linked to the Website**  
We are not responsible for the practices employed by websites linked to or from our Website nor the information or content contained therein. Often links to other sites are provided solely as pointers to information on topics that may be useful to the users of our Website and/or the iClassPro Application.

Please remember that when you use a link to go from our Website and/or the iClassPro Application to another site, our Privacy Policy is no longer in effect. Your browsing and interaction on any other site, including sites which have a link on our Website, is subject to that site’s own rules and policies. Please read over those rules and policies before proceeding.

**Data Portability**

If required by applicable law, iClassPro will comply with your request to obtain a copy of the information you have shared through our services.  If provided for by applicable law, you have rights to obtain a copy of some of the personal information that we hold on you and reuse or share it for your own purposes (“right to data portability”).

The above-stated right to data portability only applies:

  * to personal information you have provided to us (i.e. not any other information);
  * where we are processing your personal information because you have provided your consent for us to do so, or under a contract with you; and
  * when processing is carried out by automated means.

‍We can refuse your data portability request if the processing does not satisfy the above criteria.  Also, if the personal information concerns more than one individual, we may not be able to transfer the information to you if doing so would prejudice the other person’s rights.

**Cross-Border Transfers of Personal Information and Processing of Information in the United States of America**

_Notice to Residents of Countries outside of the United States of America_

iClassPro is headquartered in the United States of America.  Personal information may be accessed by us or transferred to us in the United States or to our affiliates, business partners, merchants, or service providers in the United States of America.  By providing us with personal information, you consent to the transfer and processing of your personal information within the United States of America.  iClassPro will protect the privacy and security of your personal information according to our Privacy Policy, regardless of where it is processed or stored.  

**EU-US Privacy Shield**  
iClassPro, Inc. complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information from European Union member countries. iClassPro has certified that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. Furthermore, we require third party recipients of EU citizens’ Personal Data to agree to respect these principles, and we accept liability for third parties’ processing of EU citizens’ data to the extent required by law.

If there is any conflict between the policies in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification page, please visit https://www.privacyshield.gov. You may view the list of Privacy Shield companies here.

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, iClassPro commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy policy should first contact iClassPro at the address below.

iClassPro has further committed to cooperate with the applicable Supervisory Authority in the EU with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU to the U.S. 

Under certain circumstances, these dispute resolution processes may result in your ability to invoke binding arbitration. As a U.S. company, we are also subject to the investigatory and enforcement power of the FTC regarding our compliance with the Privacy Shield Framework and this Privacy Policy, and users may direct complaints to the FTC in the event the dispute resolution processes described above is unsatisfactory.

**YOU MAY Opt-Out** **OF COMMUNICATIONS FROM US**

You may opt-out of receiving marketing communications from us by following the opt-out instructions in our communications. 

You may choose to opt out of sharing with any other parties with whom we may share your personal information; however, you may be unable to use the Services or certain features if you wish to limit such sharing.

**Your Consent**  
By using our Website and/or the iClassPro Application you consent to our collection and use of your personal information as described in this Privacy Policy. If we change our privacy policies and procedures, we will post those changes on our Web site to keep you aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances we may disclose it.

**Contacting iClassPro or the Appropriate Supervisory Authority**

_Enforcement and Independent Dispute Resolution_

_For EU residents:_

To access your information, ask questions about our privacy practices, or issue a complaint, contact us at:

iClassPro, Inc.   
1249 LL Mackey Pkwy  
Longview, TX 75605  

You have the right to  **complain to a data protection authority**  about our collection and use of your personal information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority.  The following is the contact information for the supervisory authorities in each member state: <http://ec.europa.eu/justice/data-protection/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm>.

As further explained in the Privacy Shield Principles, a binding arbitration option will also be made available to you in order to address complaints not resolved by any other means. To learn more about our privacy practices, see our Privacy Policy details.

_For non-EU residents:_

To access your information, ask questions about our privacy practices, or issue a complaint, contact us at:

iClassPro, Inc.   
1249 LL Mackey Pkwy  
Longview, TX 75605  

If your inquiry is not satisfactorily addressed, contact the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) directly ([https://ftccomplaintassistant.gov](https://benchprep.com/privacy-policy)), and afford the FTC time to attempt to resolve the issue. To learn more about our privacy practices, see our Privacy Policy details.

**_Our Commitment to Compliance with Applicable Law and Updates to Our Privacy Policy_**

_Compliance Verification and Privacy Policy Updates_

iClassPro regularly reviews, self-assesses, and verifies that the attestations and assertions made about our Privacy Shield privacy practices are true and these privacy practices have been implemented as represented and in accordance with the Privacy Shield Principles. As part of the annual compliance verification process, iClassPro will follow the steps below in an independent manner:

  1. Review this Privacy Shield policy and iClassPro’s publicly posted website privacy policy to ensure that they accurately and comprehensively describe the practices in place around collection of personal information received from the EU.
  2. Ensure that the publicly posted privacy policy indicates iClassPro’s adherence to the Privacy Shield Principles.
  3. Confirm that iClassPro’s published privacy policy regarding personal information received from the EU is prominently displayed, completely implemented, and accessible to individuals.
  4. Ensure that individuals are informed of any in-house arrangements for handling complaints and of the independent mechanisms through which they may pursue complaints.
  5. Ensure that iClassPro has implemented processes and procedures for training our employees in the execution of Privacy Shield policies, including appropriate disciplinary action for failure to follow it.

Our privacy policy may be subject to change or alteration without notice from time to time, in which case this policy remains in force until it is replaced or superseded by a newer version. In most instances, changes will be minor and posted on this page. More significant changes may be posted as a notice elsewhere, or sent to you via email.

We undertake not to reduce your rights to privacy as set out in this policy without your consent. If you have any complaints or queries, please do not hesitate to contact us.

**Contact Us**  
iClassPro, Inc.  
1249 L.L. Mackey  
Longview, TX 75605  
Phone: 877-554-6776  
Email: [support@iclasspro.com](mailto:support@iclasspro.com)

_Last updated: 8/17/18_
